CHRISTOPHE FOYER

christophe@cfoyer.com • www.cfoyer.com
United States: (+1) 816-419-6150 • France: (+33) 6-78-56-99-03
US and French citizenships; Eligible to work without restriction in the USA and EEA

Summary:

Mechanical Engineer with experience in projects in mechatronics, software, and aerospace engineering. Demonstrated track record of finding solutions to engineering challenges while operating under tight budgets.

• CAD, FEA and CFD

• Fabrication (metals, plastics, and composites)

• Engineering Hand Calculations

• Embedded Systems and Software Development

Education:

Washington University in Saint Louis

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering (3.14/4.00 GPA)

St Louis, United States Aug 2014 – Dec 2017

RWTH Aachen (Study Abroad)

'Renewable Energy Technology' | 'Mechatronics and Product Innovation'

Aachen, Germany Jun 2017 – Jul 2017

School for International Training (Study Abroad)

Reykjavik, Iceland Jun 2015 – Aug 2015

'Renewable Energy Engineering and Resource Economics'

Caen, France

Lycée Sainte Marie Série S (Science track) - French Baccalauréat; "Mention Bien" (with honours)

Sep 2010 – Jul 2013

Relevant Experience:

Temporary Works Design (TWD)

Design Engineer

London, United Kingdom

Nov 2018 - Present

- Design of bespoke equipment and assemblies for civil engineering contractors using Autodesk Inventor
- Verification of structural parameters using engineering hand calculations and finite element analysis

Tata Steel Europe

IJmuiden, Netherlands Apr 2018 – July 2018

Mechanical Engineering Intern

- Successfully built a real-time thermal simulation in Python reducing estimation error by 82.4%
- Estimating slab temperature within 21°C leading to potential savings of one million euros per year
- Organized a training session on collaborative code management (git) for the department

Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly Competition Team

Washington University in St. Louis, USA

Co-Founder and Systems Team Lead

Mar 2016 – Dec 2017

- Co-led the team to 12th place out of 138 teams at the AIAA DBF 2017 competition
- Led the systems team to design and optimize aircraft internal systems through MATLAB simulations
- Managed an operating budget of \$10,000 to purchase components and organize travel to competition
- Scheduled weekly meetings with the team and coordinated project deadlines

American Society of Mechanical Engineers

Washington University in St. Louis, USA Sep 2016 – May 2017

Event Planner

- Researched and successfully presented reasons to fund Michio Kaku's visit to campus for \$45,000
- Advised ASME members with ongoing projects on manufacturing and component selection.

Skills and Abilities:

CAD / FEA / CFD: SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, AutoCAD, XFLR5

Programming Languages: Python, MATLAB, Simulink, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Fabrication: 3D-Printing (FDM), Machining (Lathe, Mill), Composite Manufacturing

Software: Microsoft Office Suite (Excel, Word), git, Windows, Linux

Languages: Bilingual French / English; Basic German and Icelandic

Academic Projects:

Senior Design Project – Low-Cost CPV

Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Foyer, Christophe; Rangwala, Adam; and Nana, Deep, "Water Lenses for Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics" (2017). Mechanical Engineering Design Project Class. (openscholarship.wustl.edu/mems411/71/)

- Coding of FEA and ray tracing software for optics simulation in MATLAB
- Development of a sunlight tracking circuit and coding using Arduino
- Creation of a working proof of concept prototype increasing solar cell output by 860%

Independent Projects:

Printable Folding Tricopter

Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Design of a folding tricopter frame for FDM printing:

- Design of interlocking printable parts using Solidworks and Autodesk Nettfab to be 3D-printed
- Minimized weight and exterior volume while maximizing payload space

Motor Test Stand Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Design and construction of a motor test stand for Wash. U Design/Build/Fly:

- GUI development, serial communication protocol and sensor integration
- Coded in Python and Arduino C, packaged in .exe format for easy deployment to new installations
- Measures motor-propeller-battery system RPM, current, voltage, and thrust and logs output to CSV

Electric Longboard

Oct 2016 – Dec 2017

Design and construction of a custom-built electric longboard:

- CAD, FEA, and part fabrication in aluminium and FDM printing of plastic parts
- Electrical powertrain design including component selection balancing efficiency and cost
- Designed according to air travel and personal transportation regulations

Naïve Bayes Classifier

Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

Coding of a Naïve Bayes Classifier for data forecasting using simple machine learning:

- Coded a Bayesian classifier from scratch in python and tested it against test datasets
- Achieved performance to standard Bayes classifiers while supporting missing datapoints

IRIS Voice Recognition and Home Automation

Jan 2015 – May 2017

Custom-built smart home and media centre system:

- Voice recognition using google API interfacing with connected microphones
- Coded in Python 2.7 on a Raspberry Pi running a Linux-based OS (with Windows and OSX support)
- Control over house appliances and interfacing with Open Source Media Center

Robotics Test Platform

Dec 2013 - Jan 2015

Design, coding, and construction of an internet-controlled robot used for autonomous sensing and navigation testing:

- Coded in Python on Linux-based microcontrollers
- Frontend: webpage coding in HTML and UI design
- Backend: hardware interfacing and communication over IP
- Experiments in visual odometry and SLAM using OpenCV and ROS (ongoing)

Work and Volunteering Experience:

Domaine du Vivier

Le Mesnil Mauger, France

Seasonal farm hand

Jun 2015 – Aug 2017

- Maintenance and operation of farming equipment and various agricultural work
- Driver for the tossing of the hay and the loading of hay bales during the summer

I.C.C.
Volunteer

Ishinomaki, Japan

May 2014

• Construction of wooden terraces for the local community in a region devastated by the 2011 tsunami.